Hello, and welcome to Lesson 3 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
您好，欢迎来到Wolfram U的微积分入门课程第3课
Our topic for today is the elementary functions. Let’s begin with a brief overview of today’s lesson.
今天我们的主题是基本函数。让我们从今天课程的简要概述开始。
In the previous lesson, Lesson 2, we learned how our functions can be used to represent change,
在上一课第2课中，我们学习了如何使用函数来表示变化，
and we learned how to define a function, plot it, evaluate it, et cetera, but then we also learned that
我们学习了如何定义函数，对其进行绘制，对其进行计算等等，然后我们还了解到
there are many different kinds of functions. It’s quite puzzling, the number of functions you might see
存在许多不同的函数 令人困惑的是，您可能会看到的功能数量
at any one time. Here are a few graphs over here. Let’s say that’s a kind of oscillating function,
在任何时候。这是这里的一些图表。这是一种振荡函数，
and you might have an increasing function or a decreasing function, and the question is
您也可能看到递增函数或递减函数，问题是
what do you really need to study calculus in this course? Well, in this lesson what we’ll do is
在这门课程中你需要学习这些函数之中的哪些？在这节课中，
we’ll categorize the types of functions that you’ll really encounter later in the course.
我们将对您在后面课程中有可能遇到的函数进行分类。
These functions are somewhat simpler than what you might encounter in advanced mathematics,
这些函数比您在高等数学中可能遇到的函数要简单一些，
and hence they are called elementary functions, as opposed to what are called special functions.
因此，它们被称为基本函数，而不是特殊函数
Our topic of today is elementary functions, which we will study in some detail.
今天我们的主题是基本函数，我们将对其进行详细研究。
Perhaps the simplest kind of function is a linear function. For example, here is a function
也许最简单的函数是线性函数。例如，这是一个函数
f[x] = x + 3, and if you plot it, what you see is you get a straight line. That’s a linear function,
f [ x ] = x + 3，如果绘制它，您会看到一条直线。这就是一个线性函数
and in general, the function f[x] = mx + b is called a linear function, and that m over there is the slope
通常，满足此表达式：f [ x ] = mx + b的函数称为线性函数，这里的m是斜率
and the b is the y-intercept. Linear functions are rather simple. Their graphs are straight lines,
b是ÿ截距。线性函数非常简单。他们的图像是直线，
they have a slope and a y-intercept, and that’s about all.
他们有一个斜率和y轴截距。这就是它的所有性质。
Okay. To go a step further, let’s talk about power functions. A power function is also very simple.
好了。为了更进一步，让我们讨论幂函数。幂函数也非常简单。
It has a form x to the power a. Here are some power functions of a simple power
它具有 a的x次方的形式。这是一些具有简单幂次的幂函数
like 1 and 2 and 3 and 4. Let’s plot them, and what you notice is that the graphs depend upon
它们具有像1和2以及3和4之类的幂次。让我们绘制它们，您会发现图形取决于
the kind of power you have. If you have an odd degree or an odd power function,
它的幂次。如果您研究的是具有奇数次幂的函数，
then the graphs are odd. For example, the graph for x is odd, whereas the plot for x^2 will be even.
那么这些图就是关于奇函数的。例如，x的图是奇数次的函数，而x ^ 2 的图是偶数次的
These power functions are simple in the sense that the odd degree functions are odd
这些幂函数比较简单（奇数幂是奇函数，偶数幂是偶函数）
and the even degree functions are even. Now slightly harder than those are the root functions,
比这些更难一些的是根式函数
where you have things like x^(1/2), like the square root function basically. That’s just a simple way
这里有x ^（1/2）之类的东西，这就是就是平方根函数
That’s just a simple way of saying x^(1/3) in the Wolfram Language. Those functions are
在Woflram语言中表示出x^(1/3)是很简单的事情。
are a little more complicated than the earlier set because now what happens is if you look at the plots,
这些函数比起刚刚那些简单函数要更加复杂一点
they look a bit thicker over here than over there. That’s because the odd roots are defined everywhere
它们在这里看起来比那儿要厚。那是因为在我们可以在整个实数域上面求奇数根
while the even ones are only defined for positive—or non-negative, really—values of the variable.
而偶数根式仅作用于正的（或者非负的）变量。
Here’s the square root function, and the square root of a number is only defined
这是平方根函数，仅当数字是非负数的时候，
if the number is non-negative. That’s the class of power functions which are quite useful in practice.
才能定义它的根式。以上这些就是幂函数的分类，在实践中非常有用
To go a step further, let’s talk about polynomials. That over there, the function f, is a polynomial.
为了更进一步，让我们谈谈多项式。这里的函数f是一个多项式。
Now if you plot the polynomial, you get a graph. It’s a nice smooth graph, and generally speaking
现在，如果您绘制多项式，则会得到一个图形。这是一个很好的平滑图形，通常来说
if you want to find a polynomial, you need to set up a sum of this type. The a’s over here
如果要建立一个多项式，则需要此类型的总和：这里的a
are coefficients, while the powers are right over there—n, n − 1, et cetera.
是系数，而幂次在这儿： n，n -1等。
The highest power is called the degree of the polynomial. This polynomial over here
最高次幂称为多项式的次数。这个多项式
has coefficients 3, −1, 7 and 6, while the degree is 4 because you have x^4 over there.
的系数为3，-1、7和6，而次数为4，因为此处有x ^ 4。
In particular, linear functions have degree 1, quadratic functions have degree 2
特别地，线性函数的阶数为1，二次函数的阶数为2
and cubic functions have degree 3. You have this vast array of polynomials.
三次函数的阶数为3。你可以建立各种各样的多项式
They are very simple to work with, but they are incredibly useful. You have linear, quadratic,
它们使用起来非常简单，但是却非常有用。您可以使用线性，二次方，
cubic polynomials, et cetera, which we encounter all the time in the course.
三次多项式等，我们在课程中多次讨论多项式函数
Okay. To go a step further, we can talk about rational functions. A rational function is
好了，更进一步，我们可以讨论有理函数。有理函数是
simply a quotient of two polynomials, the ratio of two polynomials.
只是两个多项式的商，即两个多项式之比。
If you divide a polynomial by another, you get a rational function. Perhaps the simplest kind
如果将多项式除以另一个，则会得到有理函数。
of rational function is the reciprocal function, which is 1/x. If you plot it,
倒数函数或许能称作最简单的有理函数，即1 / x。如果把它画出来
you see the plot has got two pieces, and that’s because there is a problem at x = 0
您会看到该图有两个部分，这是因为x = 0时存在问题
where the function is not defined. You have a piece on the right and a piece on the left,
这是函数未定义的地方。原点左边和原点右边都有定义
and together they give you the reciprocal function. In general, rational functions
它们共同构成倒数函数。一般而言，有理函数
are defined everywhere, except where the denominator is zero. Whenever the function q over here is zero,
除分母为零的地方外，所有地方都定义了。每当函数q为零时
you will find that there are problems and the rational function is not defined. But apart from that,
就会出现问题，在该点处有理函数没有定义。但是除此之外
they are rather simple to work with, and again, they are incredibly useful in calculus.
它们使用起来非常简单，并且在微积分中非常有用。
Okay. Let’s go a step further and talk about algebraic functions. An algebraic function
好了，让我们更进一步，讨论代数函数。代数函数
is obtained by adding, subtracting, multiplying, dividing or taking roots,
是通过加，减，乘，除或取根获得的，
and that of course is where all the trouble lies because when you take roots, you can have
当然那是所有麻烦的根源，因为当您取根式的时候
you can have all kinds of things going wrong. Here’s a pretty complicated algebraic function.
你可能会遇到错误。这是一个非常复杂的代数函数。
It’s got square roots, cube roots, et cetera, in it, and if you plot it, there could be issues.
它里面有平方根，立方根等等，如果我们绘制它，可能会遇到问题。
There is an issue over here at zero because of the denominator, and then the function may
在0处，可能在分母上出现问题
not be defined on certain parts, so the domain is rather small typically,
函数在这些部分没有定义，因此它的定义域通常很小，
and these algebraic functions come in a variety of shapes. Although they are interesting,
这些代数函数具有多种形式。它们虽然很有趣，
they are somewhat less easy to work with, and we will probably not use them a lot at the start.
但是有时候不太容易使用，一开始我们可能不会太多地使用它们
Okay. Beyond algebraic functions, we then have the trigonometric functions, which of course
好了。除了代数函数，我们还有三角函数，当然
many of you might be familiar with. The sine, cosine, and tangent functions are
你们中的许多人可能都熟悉三角函数。正弦，余弦和切线函数都是
the trigonometric functions. Now, just a word of warning. In the Wolfram Language,
三角函数。现在，需要提醒您的一点是，在Wolfram语言中，
we always use the radian measure. If I say Sin[30], that’s not so good; you have to say Sin[π/6]
我们总是使用弧度制。比方当你需要求角度30度的正弦值时，Sin[30]并不是一个好的写法
or Sin[30 Degree] when you really want the sine of 30 degrees. Then of course you get
我们必须写成Sin[π/6]或Sin [30 Degree]。
Then of course you get the correct behavior. The 1/2’s over there came out because you used
这样您就能得到正确的结果。算出来的结果是1/2
the right notation and the right units. Keep in mind that you must always use the radian measure
因为您采取了正确的符号和正确的单位。请记住，在使用Wolfram语言工作时
when working in the Wolfram Language, or else you must say Degree like I have done over here.
我们需要使用弧度制，否则您必须像我在这里所做的那样声明Degree（度数）。
Here are the first three plots for trig functions: sine, cosine and tangent.
这是三角函数的前三个图：正弦，余弦和正切。
Okay. You can see that they are all oscillating, both sine and cosine. Then the tangent function
您会看到正弦和余弦都在震荡。而正切函数是周期的
has got these similarities because that’s where you have a problem: when you divide by zero,
the cosine function is zero, et cetera. Okay. Those are the sine, cosine and tangent functions,
余弦函数为零，等等。好了，这些是正弦，余弦和正切函数，
and sine and cosine have a period of 2π, while the tangent has a period of π only.
正弦和余弦的周期为2π，而正切的周期仅为π。
They are repetitious and they have periods, but those periods depend upon the kind of function
它们是重复的并且有周期，但是这些周期取决于函数的类型
you are working with. Of course you could have a Sin[2x], Sin[3x], et cetera,
当然，您可以构造Sin [2 x ]，Sin [3 x ]等
to get faster and faster oscillations.
震荡得越来越快的函数
Okay. Now if you take a reciprocal of the trigonometric functions, then you get
好的。现在，如果您取三角函数的倒数，那么您将得到
cosecant, secant and cotangent, which are the reciprocal trigonometric functions.
正割，余割和余切，这是三角函数的倒数。
Here are their graphs. What you see over here is that reciprocal graphs are right over there, and
这是他们的函数图。你在这儿看到的就是三角函数的倒数图
the problem is that they are not defined wherever the corresponding trig function is 0.
此处可能出现问题：如果某处它对应的三角函数值为0，则该函数在该点处没有定义。
For example, if sine happens to be zero at a point, then cosecant is not defined, et cetera,
例如，如果正弦在某个点上恰好为零，则此处余割没有定义，等等，
so there are gaps in these functions which reflect the zeros of the underlying trigonometric function.
因此这些函数中存在一些沟壑，这些沟壑处就是三角函数的零点
But they are also somewhat similar to trig functions in the sense that secant and cosecant have
但是它们和三角函数也有相似之处，
got a period of 2π while cotangent has got a period of π.
正割和余割的周期为2π，而余切线为π。
These functions are quite useful in some parts of calculus.
这些函数在微积分的某些部分中非常有用。
Okay. Going a step further, we can now talk about the exponential functions,
好了，让我们更进一步，我们现在可以继续讨论指数函数，
which are of the form a raised to the power x, so now the exponent is variable.
只不过它们的形式从a的幂变成x的幂，那么现在底数是可变的。
For example, if we look at 2^x—that’s a case when the base a is greater than 1—
举例来说，如果我们看2 ^ x，即底数a大于1的情况，
then you have an exponential growth function. Here’s a plot, and you can see quite clearly
那么您就有了指数增长函数。这是一个函数图，您可以很清楚地看到
that it is growing quite fast. On the other hand, if you take number between 0 and 1 like 0.5,
函数增长非常快。另一方面，如果您采用介于0和1之间的数字（如0.5），
then you get a decreasing function. But in any case, these functions always pass through
那么你得到一个递减函数。但是无论如何，这些函数总是通过
the point (0, 1) because a^0 = 1, as you all know from your study of indices in algebra.
点（0,1），因为a ^ 0 = 1
Exponential functions are really useful for capturing growth on one hand and decay on the other.
在描述事物增长或者减少方面，指数函数非常有用
Things like our population might grow exponentially, and certain other things
比如我们的人口可能会呈指数增长，而某些其他事物
might decay exponentially, but together, the exponential functions of different types give you
可能会呈指数衰减。不同类型的指数函数是您在微积分中
a powerful way of expressing rates of growth or decay in calculus.
表达增长或衰减速率的有效方法
They are incredibly important and you should know them well.
它们非常重要，您应该非常了解它们。
Finally, we’ll talk about the logarithmic functions, which are defined as log[x] to base a,
最后，我们将讨论对数函数，这些函数定义为基于a log [ x ] ，
and they are the inverses of the exponential functions. Here is a graph of Log[x].
它们是指数函数的逆函数。这是Log [ x ] 的图形。
Keep in mind that in the Wolfram Language, the base is set to e,
请记住，在Wolfram语言中，底数设置为e，
but if you want a different base, then you would say that over here and you would get back Log[x],
但是如果您想使用其他底数，那么您可以在这里声明，然后返回Log [ x ]，
but now to the base 1/4. They are very similar in some sense to the exponential functions
但现在底数是1/4。在某种意义上，对数函数与指数函数非常相似
because they are in fact the inverses. The logarithmic functions are quite useful, but as you can see,
因为它们实际上互为逆函数。对数函数非常有用，但是如您所见，
they grow much slower than the exponentials and they have their own uses.
它们的增长比指数慢得多，它们有自己的用途
Okay. We’ve talked about a fairly wide variety of elementary functions,
好了，我们讨论了各种各样的基本函数，
and to summarize today’s lesson, we have many different forms of functions
现在来总结今天的课程，我们有许多不同形式的函数
and many different kinds of graphs studied today. You can have linear functions,
以及今天研究的许多不同种类的图。你可以有线性函数，
polynomial functions, rational functions, trig functions, et cetera, and together they already required
多项式函数，有理函数，三角函数等。
for studying calculus in this course, for the most part.
在本课程的大多数内容中，都需要用到它们。
Okay. We are basically done with today’s lesson. In the next lesson we will cover limits,
好的。今天的课程基本上已经完成。在下一课中，我们将介绍极限，
so you really start doing calculus in this course next time. But before doing that,
下节课你将真正开始进行微积分计算。但是在那之前
do look at today’s lesson in the notebook that’s supplied to you, look at the accompanying exercises,
请在提供给您的笔记本上复习今天的课程并且完成随附的练习，
go over them. You can only learn mathematics by doing, so spend some time reviewing,
您需要亲自实践才能学会数学，因此您需要花一些时间进行复习
solve the exercises, et cetera, and you should be in good shape to join me next time for Lesson 4.
并且完成练习。接着您应该能轻松学习第4课了。
Thank you very much. I hope you enjoyed today’s lesson. I’ll see you next time.
非常感谢您的聆听。希望您享受这节课程，我们下节课再见。